Podcasting 2.0 for June 27,
2025, episode 226. Tick, Nick.
Hello, everybody. Time once
again for the board meeting.
Yep, it's where all the luminaries
gather together for Podcasting 2.0.
We discuss it all. What's happened, what
is happening, and what will still happen.
Yes, it's all right here.
In fact, we are the only boardroom that will
actually miss the blue screen of death.
I'm Adam Curry here in the heart of
the Texas Hill Country and in Alabama.
The man who always has an
antenna emanating signal waves.
Say hello to my friend on the other
end, the one, the only, Mr. Dave Jones.
You pulled that one off. That
was a linguistic achievement.
I stumbled. No, I stumbled
a little bit, a little bit.
I heard it, but it was still good. I mean,
you were trying to do a complex rotation.
Very, very complex, yes, because it's
an antenna emanating signal waves,
which is an example in
the podcast images tag.
I was like, that is very cool.
I don't think I could even type
that, much less say it on the fly.
Oh, man.
Yeah, this is funny. Like, we're
talking to our secret guest.
Our guest, yeah, our secret guest, yes.
Pre-show, and then in the live stream
in the boardroom, somebody, see,
Brooklyn said, girl?
Question mark.
Like, wait, a girl voice in the boardroom?
We have a girl on the show? No way. Have
we ever had a girl on the show before?
Yeah, Dame Jennifer.
Oh, yes, that's true. You're right.
I think that's the only one, right?
It's kind of atrocious, and
it's not- It's horrible.
It's not terrible.
It's not like it's us.
I mean, it's just they don't show up.
Maybe it is us, and that's
why they don't show up.
I don't know.
I'll wait to tell you my
accidental misogyny story
until we invite her into the boardroom.
You only have one?
Oh, yeah. I have one. This is
the accidental misogyny story.
Oh, not the on-purpose misogyny story.
Yeah, right. Yeah, there's lots of
those, but this is the accidental one.
I got it.
By the way, I mentioned the opening,
but did you notice that
Microsoft has indeed said they
are going to remove the
blue screen of death?
The frowny face.
Replace it with what?
Ah, I don't know.
Let me see what they say about that.
But, you know, the blue screen is.
You know what the blue screen is.
I don't have to tell you.
Oh, yeah.
They're going to replace it
with- Are you ready for it?
A purple screen of death.
The black screen of death.
Oh, God.
But it won't have the frowny face.
That, I have to say, is the most insulting
thing I've ever seen on a computer.
Is that stupid frowny face?
You have always been very annoyed
by patronizing error messages.
It drives you up the wall.
Like, what, like, like, I remember
one time you said that, like,
how annoyed you were with that
chrome when it doesn't air.
Oh. Oops. Oops. And has,
with the X's on the eyes.
Uh-huh.
Yeah. No, this is- This irritates you.
Yes. It's insulting. I
want a detailed log.
A log. Give me a log file.
I want to know what's going on.
Yeah, man.
I've become a log man.
Wait.
I should probably rephrase that.
What? Why do you do that? Like,
eight minutes into the show.
And we haven't even introduced
our girl guest. I know.
We've already got a show
title in the boardroom.
Log man.
I mean, like, it's just ridiculous.
That is, that's out of control.
This is out of control.
But I have.
I mean, the importance of logs and having
a log that spits out and grepping,
you know, just for what you want to see.
It's just, it's phenomenal.
I really love it.
I am a developer, Dave.
Be careful.
You are.
You are becoming an, you are becoming
more of a developer on a daily basis.
You're, you're starting to talk like once.
That's the, you know,
in the chat, in chat,
you're starting to like
do the, do the lingo.
Yeah.
Which I'm, I'm, I mean, I'm a huge fan of.
I think this is important progress
in your personal development.
I would agree.
And man, again, the AI, I have a
new, AI is a new acronym for me.
That's ready for it?
Another one?
Yes.
Because I first had almighty intelligence,
but now AI is accelerated idiocracy.
That's my new, that's
my new acronym for AI.
It's a little complex.
It's so stupid.
It really is.
You ask it the simplest things and
it'll go off and just add stuff.
So the other day I had a
perfectly good script.
I had a, you know, like a dry
run option, which is great.
So I go, okay, this is
what it's going to do.
All right.
This makes sense.
So then I removed the dry run
option and it doesn't work.
I'm like, what's going on?
And for some reason it decided to just
comment out the base URL with a little
comment that says, add actual
URL here when ready to deploy.
Oh, that's terrible.
And it had changed the URL that it was.
So it was the correct URL and it,
for, you know, the API endpoint,
they just commented out with something
different and said, you know,
replace this with the, I mean, that is,
that can only be stupid AI cut
and paste from some other script.
It had that it had that it
had that it found something
and just added it in for no reason.
That that's, um, so that, that
is the, I have stumped you.
I have stumped you.
That's what happens.
That's what happens when, um,
and when it tries to go like off script
and it's just grabbing stuff from other,
because, oh, we, we, we, we, we still
forget that this thing is just pulling.
It's just pulling things from other
material that's already seen before.
Like when it tries to, when it tries to
like a freestyle, you go, it's like,
it just goes completely off the rails.
If you, if you're not giving it
something, it can understand in small,
tiny bite-sized chunks.
But I, I, I would say that the real
issue is that it does that all the time.
It literally does that all the time.
This always pulling stuff from somewhere.
And unless you explicitly say, do not do
this, do only all caps, only change this.
If you don't do that, then it
just, it'll just do stuff.
It's a, it's a, but forget all that.
It's made me a pretty good code debugger.
That's why I love the log files.
Like why, why is it giving me this output?
Oh, okay.
I see.
So we, uh, um, we all celebrated 20
years of podcasting on Apple, which,
um, somehow, um, no one tagged me,
which is okay, which is, I was,
I was looking for you in the
list of, Oh, forget about it.
Podcast.
Yeah, no, no, forget about it.
So, uh, to celebrate in our own way,
I figured I would play the, uh,
my favorite video of Steve jobs.
May he rest in peace.
Uh, when he introduced podcasting in
front of mall, um, what's his name?
Uh, uh, Walt Mossberg,
Walt Mossberg and Kara Swisher
at the D3 conference in 2005,
a mere hours after he and I had had a
personal one-on-one private meeting.
Just if you were to eventually get
into selling paid audio stuff.
Well, I, you could, you
could try to sell podcasts,
but the whole phenomenon is so great.
It's free.
And I think what we're going
to see is an advertising
supported model emerge
just like free radio.
Here's another one.
Adam Curry is, uh, one of the guys
that invented podcasting and, uh,
he has a podcast called the daily source.
Let me go ahead and subscribe to that.
And, uh, we can go listen to his latest
one and wait for daily source code show.
Radio number 180.
Something remarkable is happening here.
Radio is springing free of the regulated
gatekeepers who've managed what you can
hear since radio was invented.
It's jumping into the hands of anyone at
all with something or nothing to say.
A million dollars worth of
airplanes scrapped to my ass.
Transmix.
And the next generation
radio content in my ears.
We don't need us.
We don't need you, Transmix.
I like to think I'm
flying into the future.
Podcasting is Adam Curry.
That's right. It's show number 180 and
it's Friday, everybody. Thank God.
The power.
I've actually had to restart
the show three times.
My Mac has been acting
up like a motherfucker.
I don't know what's going on.
I think it's, uh, something to
do with, uh, the file system.
Okay.
Wait, wait for Kara Swisher.
What does she go to right away?
How do you control, say, dirty stuff?
I mean, we're going to
have an explicit flag
on these like we do the
music so you can...
Shut up, Kara, with your dirty stuff.
Scissorship.
By the way, if you ever
listen to, uh, to Pivot,
she has the dirtiest mouth
of all on the podcast.
It's unbelievable.
Always dropping F-bombs.
Now, how, one question I've
always had about that clip...
Yes.
Is, was Steve...
Did he do that episode on purpose?
100%.
Uh, that felt like a manufactured shock.
He knew, he knew exactly
what he was doing.
No doubt about it.
Because people say,
well, wow, man, that's,
that shows you how a
live demo can go wrong.
I'm like, no, no.
He did, he did this on purpose.
Oh, yeah.
He knew exactly what he was doing.
Yeah.
He's not a, he's not the kind of guy who
does something on stage without rails.
Uh, no kidding.
Everything is rehearsed.
Everything is down to the last minute.
And, uh, have I ever told you
about the private meeting?
You probably heard some of it.
A little bit.
Yeah.
So, you know, uh, Eddie Q, actually.
Eddie Q.
He called.
He says, yeah, you got time
for a meeting with Steve?
Uh, yeah.
Now, let me check my calendar.
Eddie Q.
Let me check.
Yes.
See if I can fit it in.
But, you know, right.
He, he greeted me at the door.
Uh, there was a private
like conference room.
This was in San Diego, I
think at the D3 conference.
And right away, I'm
like, wow, he's lankier.
He has a little bit of a hunch
in his back and he has a lisp.
I'd never noticed the list before.
And right away is like, what can
we do to make podcasting better?
What, how can we help out?
Um, I'm like, well, you can do stuff
like don't break audio hijack pro,
which those guys,
uh, you know, they, they found out
about years later because that, uh,
the RIAA wanted them to disable that.
So you could record directly
from, you know, from your Mac.
So don't break that.
Yeah.
That was back in the days of, uh,
back in the days of when, uh,
the MPAA was also trying
to crack down on DVD encryption.
All of that.
Yeah.
All of that stuff.
And, um, uh, then he kicked Eddie Q out.
And then it was just the two of us.
He said, you know, we've
been watching you.
Creepy.
Yeah.
Through my Mac.
He says, no, no, no.
We saw, we saw that you
were using your Mac drive.
You can remember those days.
You could mount it on your desktop.
Remember that?
A Mac drive show up as a little volume.
And, uh, he says, you know, you've
been serving your MP3s from there.
I said, yeah, he says, so we noticed
the bandwidth just going crazy.
And, uh, and then he came to, and somehow
got to me and I said, no, just let him go.
Let's see what he's doing.
Let's let him.
So he took, he took credit for that.
I'm sure part of his, at least is true.
So I appreciated that.
And then it was like, you know, but
it just asked all these questions.
And then it was the craziest thing.
He's like, well, I really just
want to ask you if it's okay.
If we put podcasting into
iTunes and the iPod, I'm like,
this guy actually asking me that you,
what do you want my blessing?
I didn't say that, but I was
thinking, he said, yeah, sure.
He said, okay, good.
And, uh, then, uh, and I said,
and I'll give you the directory.
We have about 5,000, uh,
podcasts in our directory.
OPML, the open, uh, opml.ipodder.org.
That was a OPML.
Um, what do you call the,
um, what is that called?
Where are you?
Inclusion?
Yeah.
With inclusions.
So I had, I had country
managers and each of
those country managers had their own, you
know, like for tech, for
politics, et cetera.
And everybody was just creating their own
OPML file and we using it as includes.
And so you could start at the top
and then you could just drill down.
It would always be, you
know, a fresh listing.
It was a pretty cool idea.
Yeah.
That's great.
When the list is only, you know, a
few, a few hundred or a few thousand.
It got unwieldy.
It works perfectly.
Yeah.
And, uh, and so of course then
when, when they debuted it,
the big disappointment was,
look at the homepage.
Oh, NPR, BBC, you know, it had, they had
all mainstream stuff and, and it was really
the independent people who had built it.
And that was definitely a disappointment,
but, but, but he had already,
they had already built it all out.
He was just wanting like, totally.
It sounds like to me what he wanted
was, um, cotton gin, cotton gin.
I can't sell out if I didn't
get any money for it.
There was no money changed hands.
Yeah.
Your, your, your big podcast checks
are still rolling in these days.
Yeah.
People, there are people who
think I'm a billionaire.
Oh man, you, you must've
made it from podcasting.
Yeah.
I must've made a billion off that, uh,
once Apple bought podcasting from you.
So, okay.
Yeah, sure.
You, you, you, you, uh,
you made one RSS tag.
We've made like 20 something.
We should be like the rich, we
should be like 20 billionaires.
Oh, easily.
The check is in the mail, baby.
Yeah.
Um, but like, uh, I guess
the thing he, to me,
it seems clear that
what he wanted by doing
that song and dance,
where he brings you in and ask your
blessing or whatever it is, he
wants, he wants to turn you into an
advocate for what they're doing.
Yeah.
And, and I would say without
a doubt, um, some, I mean,
Microsoft might've done it with
the Zune, but, uh, Apple, you
know, it, we were using the iPod.
That was the whole point.
That was the whole point of,
uh, what are we drinking?
Pabst Blue Ribbon.
Oh, this is a bubbly, B-U-B-L-Y.
Orange, orange cream.
That is a Michael Bublé's a drink.
It's a Bublé.
You've never, you've never
seen him do the ads for it.
Oh, really?
Yeah.
Yes.
I'm just, I'm drinking
a Bublé orange cream.
This is a top notch.
Top notch.
Uh, we have a special guest who I'd like to
bring in, if it's okay with you, uh, Mr.
Jones.
Open the door.
Okay.
Uh, our guest today is chief
strategy officer at Soundstack,
my favorite person I've ever
had a meeting with that
didn't result in business
and the best name for
any on-air position in
radio or podcasting.
Rocky Thomas.
Yeah, I did some actual production.
Wow.
Oh my gosh.
That's awesome.
Thank you.
Yeah, I'll send it.
I'll send it to you.
You can put it on your
phone as a ringtone.
I got WWF intro music.
I felt like I was back in the booth.
That's awesome.
Now, did I get it all right there, Rocky?
Rocky, you are the chief
strategy officer of Soundstack.
Yes, you did.
And just, just to make sure I am a
girl, just in case anyone's curious.
Yes.
We thought so.
Yeah.
We were, we figured.
We were pretty sure.
Yeah.
And so you've had all these cool
titles like chief strategy officer,
chief revenue officer.
None of this used to
exist back in the day.
I always saw it was made up stuff.
But.
No.
You have, it's a, it's a real job.
And it's a real job.
And I'm always happy to see,
cause I think you're just a, a,
a radio geek like myself.
I'm always happy to see someone do
something kind of related in the industry.
Yeah.
It's, it's been, I would say that my, my,
what I'm known for is I like startups.
I love audio.
I love radio and I'm really
good at making money.
That's kind of like the.
You're hired.
You're ready to go.
And I really, and I do like,
I'm very good at explaining
things that are not in the market
yet and trying to make it, you know,
normal for people to understand it.
So I'm kind of like the translator.
Translator.
Yeah, exactly.
Yes.
That's an important role.
It is.
And it's, it's, I would
say that, you know,
when I first started
streaming with broadcast.com
with Mark Cuban's company, oh
my gosh, I'm going way back.
Oh, stop, stop, stop.
Yikes.
Because we just had a
meeting where this came up.
Now, broadcast.com was just
basically a big hoax, wasn't it?
They were using the real media server,
which is probably my age, 10 years and one.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
It was like, I think it was 16K.
And he came in to all the radio
groups and said, Hey, listen,
I'll stream you for free,
but I'm taking all your ad inventory.
He was actually doing
like pre-rolls on that.
And then perhaps one of the,
yeah, the smartest guy.
I mean, he made what?
3.2 billion on that deal.
Well, he sold it.
That was the thing.
Yeah.
I think it was, I always felt it
was just about the domain name.
Oh yeah.
Broadcast.com.
Everyone's going to go to broadcast.com.
They'll never go to radio.com
or, or anything else.
Yeah.
I don't know if he actually was selling
it or he sold the, the idea of it,
but the fact that he had
advertising tied around it.
And I remember when he sold, I was at
a radio in conference and he, I mean,
the guy was glowing.
I mean, he just got paid
free to like 3.2 billion.
Who isn't?
And he literally sat there and was
telling all of these radio CEOs,
you want to know how I made this money?
I made it off of your content,
your content, your content.
And I'm like, Oh, yay.
My job just got easier.
That's awesome.
Wow.
But yeah, I've been, so I've been,
I would say I started developing
in the late nineties on this.
And then I actually used to develop
websites and do all this fun stuff.
And, but I would say I've gone well
between the tribes, meaning I absolutely.
Still love over here, over there, radio.
I just got back from Europe
for a show called Red Tech,
which is all the C-level guys over
in the radio groups and from Europe.
It's kind of crazy because radio
is alive and well over there.
I mean, you go to Netherlands and
everything pretty frequently at them.
I mean, it's, they're still in the DAB.
They still promote their,
like their, their shows.
I would say podcasting is just starting
to kind of emerge on that side.
I would say UK is definitely ahead
of the game, but it's exciting.
I saw Germany.
Oh yeah.
Germany is doing better.
Yep.
They're doing really well as well.
The Netherlands has a very tight
radio culture because of its size.
And you basically have a signal,
you got repeaters everywhere.
So you have a signal
across the whole country.
And, you know, and so the car
radio listening is still huge.
Every taxi I was in, they're
still listening to FM.
I did not see one Spotify.
I did not see any, anybody.
And we're talking, you know, young to old,
everything else that was
being driven around.
And it's just interesting
because it's, you know,
we kind of have that different philosophy
here in the States, but you know, yeah,
I would say I've been very lucky.
I would, my parents probably
thought I was, you know,
peddling porn and growing weed in
the mountains for the first,
like, you know, 20 years.
Cause they're like, you
don't have a real job.
And I was like, no, it's
going to be a real thing.
Mom, I tell you, it's going to be great.
You're going to be proud of me one day.
So, you know, but it's been good.
It's, and I would say it
probably like around 2012,
2010 is like when
podcasting and everything
started to, you know, have some sort of
fruition, which was pretty exciting.
Yeah.
It was only seven years later.
I mean, it was brutal,
but you know, and yes.
So chief revenue officer,
chief strategy officer,
I've been selling a lot
and I wanted to kind
of move more into playing
with folks like you.
I'm trying to strategize
this industry a little
bit better so I can
figure out how I can get
what you like to call the PIC, the podcast
industrial complex working with the IP.
I call it the IPC, the
independent podcast creator.
So I'm trying to kind of,
yeah, do you like that?
I thought it was a pretty good saying.
So I'm trying to figure out
how we can kind of, you know,
get the standards more out
there and promote them.
Um, I recently did a little IAB call
with the audio lab trying to explain,
you know, some of the podcasting
2.0 new stuff that's coming out.
And they were like, huh?
Well, it was interesting.
I think that, um, really what I was
trying to explain is, you know,
the standard that we did with downloads,
cause I was part of that standard, um,
and like writing that in 2014 and 2016.
You worked at IAB, didn't you?
No, no.
I just, I just co-chaired the group.
I went through torturous.
I, I'm sure a lot of people who are
listening were on that with me.
It was two years to trying to figure
out what we were all were doing.
And, um, I thought it was gonna
be a formal, quite frankly.
I thought the download
standard was going to be
like a three-year deal just because I just
thought it was going to go
to streaming a lot faster.
And it had, it's nine years later,
we're still kind of, and that's fine.
I mean, we have a stable currency.
It's kind of like, I look at it as
like the U S dollar versus crypto.
I mean, it's very stable-ish.
And I think that, um, it's just as
much of a scam as the U S dollar.
Yeah.
I like that comparison.
Exactly.
It's a scam, but it's a, but it's a scam.
Everybody understands.
Yeah.
Stable.
And I would say that I would, I
would love consumption metrics.
I mean, I, that's what we do
on the linear streaming side.
It's, I kind of understand that.
That's why I've been really excited
about some of the latest, um, yeah,
the latest developments
and, you know, within podcasting 2.0,
I'm a huge fan of like what we're
doing right now, live broadcasting.
I think it works for certain shows.
I don't think it's going to work
for all shows, but I think the,
I look at it like if
I was a high school kid and
I wanted to like broadcast
my local high school sports, I would
be totally using this because I could
broadcast live and I can archive it.
It's just, there's a lot of opportunity
there, which is really cool.
And that's kind of what's interesting
is that, um, I, I find it's, um,
we're really lacking
on young people getting into podcasting
because of the, well, I just do a,
an IG live or I do a
TikTok or do whatever.
And, you know, as long as I
get like, by the way, uh,
Rocky is in the splits for today's show.
So show her some love boost in.
I wanted, she is, I don't
think she's ever seen the,
the magic that is receiving sats.
It's, uh, you're really going to love it.
The streaming sats as well, you know,
get your fountain app and
look at it right now.
You should already be getting sats.
I am looking.
And, um, at least I hope that's
where everything falls down.
It's amazing.
Any of this stuff works at all.
Um, but so, yeah, but you, you know, it's
like, are kids still into the idea of live
radio broadcasting or live audio
broadcasting or do they, I mean,
it seems like everyone's
just, well, it's gotta, it's gotta be, uh,
certainly live has gotta be video
and I gotta be on my phone.
I gotta be turning it around
and doing this stuff.
And what, what are you seeing out there?
You know, it's, I would agree.
I would definitely say that it's become
with the Gen Z folks, especially,
it's definitely become more
of a visual medium to them.
But I also see the other side.
I think it's kind of split.
I think you have some
kids who are going to sit
on the couch and watch videos all day and,
you know, and doom scroll or
scroll into reels forever.
And then I, I look at my own
kids who are in that, you know,
the age group who they're
busy, they're podcast first
listeners because they're,
they're riding horses,
they're doing stuff outside.
So I think you're always going to
have that split of kids who are,
want to, you know, consume.
And I also think that now
you're starting to see
more digital distribution of on the video
side with live sports.
I do, I, I hate to be overly optimistic,
but I do believe that live
is going to come back
just because if we can
figure out a way that we
can get social commenting happening at the
same time where they
have that involvement,
because that's really
the bread and butter of
that generation is the ability
to engage with content live.
I think that's going to unlock.
And I know that has a lot, a lot of
problems around it, but I think that's,
I mean, look at this show.
This is what makes it exciting.
The boardroom.
I mean, even though
agenda is the same way,
it's being able to interact
with that community.
Is it going to work for every single, like,
could I see like Radiolab wanting to do
something like this?
No.
I mean, they're more into the whole
sonic sound and design and they're more.
Radiolab, Radiolabs,
Radiolab, Radiolab, Radiolab.
Yeah.
Those guys.
Yes, that.
But I think it's, there's a place for it.
But I, so I think certain shows,
it's definitely going to be an
additive and it's going to really
drive that live element.
And I think some stuff is
just not going to work.
It's just, I could say the
same thing about the video.
I mean, if I'm putting, I don't
know, like some sort of like serial,
for instance, on YouTube, it's
not just called a documentary.
I mean, it's just, so I
think there's going to
be certain formats that
are going to work with it.
But I think what the strength
of what we're doing, you know,
in the podcasting 2.0 is just
giving people those options.
I think where we need to kind of focus on
moving forward is like, how do we, how do
we, how do we have the
conversations and the marketing
and really translating
that to the consumer?
Because it is kind of feeling, you know,
it's still kind of geeky, you know,
and it's really, it's, it's tough.
It's, it's just like crypto because everyone
has a different word for everything.
And how can we, how can
we make it into something
that people can consume
easily digest, try to
use, you know, words that they
understand like chat, you know?
And I think that's where we kind of
need to move forward a little bit more,
but I'm pretty excited.
I, I think that, I think Gen
Z is going to hop onto this.
I think that they're just right now,
not really, not really into the, the,
they're into the video side, but
that's also going to go away as
they become adulting and they realize they
can't sit in front of a screen all day.
Yeah.
How old are your kids, Rocky?
How many do you have?
I have two, 22 and 20.
Oh goodness.
Yeah.
That's the, yeah, I've got, I've got 23, 21
and 15 and the 20, the 23 and the 21 are
like the, the 23 year old, she's,
she's, she listens to podcasts a lot.
The 21 year old doesn't, but he, he's
like, they, you know, they really,
they were heavy in TikTok
world for a while.
And then that they, they told me,
they both told me, they're like,
we don't ever look at TikTok anymore.
That the TikTok thing has sort of,
it, it peaked and now it's just in a,
everybody went back to
Instagram is basically.
I would totally agree with that.
That's what my, my kids
are pretty social light.
We were kind of, I wouldn't say
we're overprotective parents,
but I would say that we're tend to
be slightly conservative parents.
And so we, even though we
were both in technology
is probably the reason why we're so gated.
That's why, yeah, yeah.
It's, we were pretty gated
about it, but I would say,
I would totally agree with you.
I, the comments I get, they were
never in, they never actually,
both of them never downloaded
TikTok because, you know, I, we
scared them about, you know,
China is going to have all your data.
I mean, so I would say that
what I've been hearing
is that now it's just TikTok shops.
It's, it's, it's gotten
over-commercialized and
let me tell you for a person who's kind
of an ad tech girl, I definitely
believe in balancing the,
the content with the message.
If you are going to do advertising,
it's killing me a little bit
right now when I'm hearing the
expanding spot loads are
happening on podcasts
because my inner sales
manager is like, you
need to increase rate, you don't
need to increase your supply.
You know, it's like, keep
the supply constricted,
but it's really hard
because everybody else is
doing it and they want to go ahead and
make sure they're making as much money.
And it's, that's where
it does make me sad.
And I would say that a
lot of these guys who
do personal endorsements
should take a page
from the radio guys because
the radio guys were
really good about personal endorsements.
They would change the
creative, like all the time.
They had three different demos.
I mean, have you ever heard
personal endorsement on the,
over there radio side back in the day?
It was, it was always changing.
It's, I feel that being as creative as
they should be, they should really,
if they are going
to be doing personal endorsement, which I
do absolutely love because it does work.
It needs to have a better thought
about how you're going to constantly,
so it doesn't burn out.
And so there's little elements
like that, but kind of,
I'm hoping that we're going
to get better, not worse.
No, Soundstack does, but I see
Soundstack does programmatic though.
So you have like, so do you
regulate that internally?
I mean, do you have, do you
say we're, we're going to put,
do you have your own limits?
If somebody says, Hey, we want to
stick 17 ads in this, uh, you know,
hour and a half program.
Are y'all like, no, we're not.
No.
At the end of the day, we're, we're,
this is where we're very much
in line with like independence
and it's up to the publisher to decide
what they want to do with their content.
Um, we're just the, the positive
enablers to help them make money,
create the pipes between
supply and demand, provide the
hosting, the analytics, the metrics,
but we don't ever want
to put our, like our philosophies.
We definitely try to guide, like whenever
I'm talking to publisher, I'm like,
Hey, your spot rate's
getting a little bit heavy.
Um, you know, your spot load.
And I really try to help them and,
you know, shepherd them into that.
But at the end of the day, it's not for
us to tell publishers what they do,
what kind of content they have.
I mean, that's why, I mean, the open
standards project is really, you know, great.
I, I, we are big supporters of
that and it's up to the publisher.
I just wish they wouldn't do it.
I mean, that's all, but we don't, we
don't dictate what the publishers do.
How many, uh, so, okay, so you, Soundstack
does a lot of different things,
but you want to just run, run down
for us and let us know what you do.
Yeah, absolutely.
I would say that, uh, first
and foremost, we're, you know,
hosting a distribution company.
We, we go both ways.
Uh, we do streaming and
all the other, you know,
IC and HLS and all that fun stuff, as
well as, uh, podcasting on demand
and even stuff in between, like, uh,
someone might have
a fast channel that they want to go ahead
and make a podcast and keep the ad,
the Scuddy markers in there.
We can actually take a video
channel, make it an audio channel.
We just recently did AP news where
they had a whole bunch of like, uh,
like small bites of news and then we
created a linear station for that.
So we like to manipulate, you know,
content to the benefit of
the publisher so they can
get as much listener consumption as
possible, kind of like create it once and,
you know, find out, find an
audience for it everywhere.
So that's definitely core
with that definitely comes
all of the analytics
and all of the listener
metrics and all the fun stuff on that.
And then we also are very strong
in ad technology and ad tech.
So SSPs, ad servers, um, all the demand
and supply connections, direct ad serving.
If people want that as well,
we have our own stack on that.
And then, um, we also provide, uh,
a lot of people don't know this,
but we're also the owners of live 365, which
have over 4,500, um, creators on there.
So we're, we're, it's, and they're
smaller creators, a lot of, uh,
churches, some religion.
Uh, we also have a lot of college, uh,
college stations or people
who just want to do 24 seven.
I don't know, Wagnerian opera, who knows?
I mean, it's like, if you're
into that or, you know,
so you have a lot of those
type of stations on there.
And what makes us different
with live 365 is that
we actually cover all the royalties with
the professional rights organizations.
So that's like ASCAP,
EMI, CSAC, SoundExchange.
We have licensing in Canada.
We just fired up Mexico as well.
So it's kind of like a one-stop shop.
You get the play out, the encoder.
I know.
I think Adam, you have
one of your stations.
I think Fred FM's on there as well.
So hello, hello, Fred.fm.
Yeah, baby.
Yes.
I'm going to give you a little plug.
And so, um, we're, we're definitely, we
work with very large, um, large, you know,
publishers and enterprise level,
but we also work with, uh,
the smaller creators as well.
So, um, yeah, the only thing we don't do
is that we don't create our own content.
So, uh, we enable it.
So we don't, we don't have any type of
content and we don't ever sell directly.
So we don't ever want to
compete with our publishers.
We just want to make them successful.
So is it, what is the biggest
piece of the, of the business?
Is it the ad, the ad market?
I would say that it's about 50, 50.
We break it up into
platform as we like to say,
which would be more of
the hosting distribution.
And then the other side
would be marketplace.
It's about a 50, 50 split
that we're at right now.
Hmm.
Interesting.
So you, but you're, you're a host,
you're a hosting company cause
you host podcasts directly.
Yes.
Yes, we do.
And you also do provide services to
other podcast hosting companies.
Yes.
Like for instance, I mean,
Todd's been very public.
We do, um, uh, provide programmatic
services for like blueberry, for example.
And, and it's interesting cause we are,
what's a little bit different
that a lot of folks may
not know is that we're a
hundred percent self-funded.
We don't have any investment.
And so we have over 80
full-time employees and, um,
we were really like that independence
because it's, I've been
through companies where
they start getting even
minority majority investment.
And your roadmap kind of gets a
little bit, you know, wonky because,
you know, that's what they want
to do and they're your investors.
So we've really tried
to keep it independent.
I say our best ideas come from
publishers or the industry.
We're like, Hey, we
need to solve for this.
So we really do try to solve
problems in the industry
as much as we possibly can, especially
if it's going to help a
whole bunch of publishers.
So, and yeah, so we're a little bit
different on that, but it's, uh, we, it is,
it is definitely, uh, I would say
different when you are self-funded
than if you have
investment money for sure.
Is that, is, is that get tricky?
Does that, does that get,
does get to be a complicated
relationship sometimes between, uh,
well, you're hosting and
there's helping the hosts.
I mean, like, well, yeah, we're, but at
the end of the day, we don't ever, we,
we don't ever put our, we provide services
sometimes, uh, I mean, it's crazy.
We work with pretty much everybody in the
industry, even the big walled garden guys.
And it just depends on what they need.
Sometimes they just need,
uh, one of our elements.
Like we have this one
product called splice that
allows you to take a linear stream and
then chunk it up either
via metadata triggers or
time triggers to make it on
demand or into a podcast format.
Sometimes people just use us for
our licensing and royalty API.
So since we have to pay royalties, we've
gotten really, really good at, um,
at going through all those log
files and all the performances
and making sure you're not paying, getting
charged for like a promo when
it's not, cause let me tell you,
our AA doesn't come back and
say, Hey, listen, you had 10,000 promo.
We got to give you money back.
They don't do that.
So it's really kind of making
sure that we definitely
want creators to get paid and that
includes musicians, but we just want
to make sure that it's being accurate.
So a lot of folks just use us for one
element and then we're fine with that.
You don't have to take the full stack.
So it's just because you host with us does
not mean you have to be in marketplace.
I mean, we, we actually host a lot of, um,
NPR stations who have
nothing to do with the
open marketplace, which
is absolutely fine.
Um, it just really is about
enabling the publisher
to be successful and it's tough right now.
And we really try to keep how much
money we make and our margins,
like as skinny as possible,
because we know that if we charge publishers
too much that we, and they go away,
we no longer, and we don't have podcasters
and we don't have radio stations.
We really no longer have an industry.
So it's really making
sure that we're keeping
the vibrancy going on that
side and keeping it healthy.
Were you ever behind the mic in radio?
Okay, so you think, you
think Dave, you think,
so I did a stint once
and it was totally for
a free ski pass in
Colorado because it's the,
the Colorado ski country
was looking to lobby
group and they were looking for a show.
So of course the sales person's
like, we could sell this.
So I used to do a, uh, it
was called fresh tracks.
It was like five, five o'clock
to seven o'clock in the morning.
And I'll be honest with you.
It was totally just so I
could get, I was poor.
I just started in radio.
I had no money and I wanted a, I wanted
a free lift ticket to all the, uh,
all the ski resorts in Colorado.
So I did that for two years, but not ever
like I would say as a full-time gig.
No.
Surprising.
Should I?
Color, color, color me surprised.
So, so I first, um, heard of you and I'm
sure you get this a lot because I heard pod
Cochran talking about you that he'd met
you somewhere at a podcast conference.
He was like, yeah, Rocky Thomas and
Rocky Thomas, this and Rocky Tom,
Rocky Thomas about the
chapter art and image and this and Rocky.
And I'm like, who is this dude?
This is, I got to meet this dude.
And of course it was you.
Um, so, so you, you have a lot
of ideas about some of the, uh,
2.0 tags or the namespace
tags that, that we've worked
on that we have in use.
Do you want to talk about that?
Yeah.
So, I mean, it was interesting.
I was looking at the chapters and
when I saw that, you know, it was,
it was sometimes some
things are so obvious.
You don't think about it,
but I was like, yeah,
talking to Todd and I'm like, wait, okay.
So those chapters are actually
pinging something, right?
So it's pulling an image from someplace.
See, I am not as technical as you guys.
I am like C minus.
I understand concepts, but I'm, I, I can
bring down a network, but I can't bring one
back up if that tells you anything.
So it's like, I understand they,
I'm like the worst person you
ever want to have work for you.
Cause I get into stuff I shouldn't
be, but I'm like, listen, if,
if the image is getting
pulled, then we actually can
use that as ad tracking.
I mean, that's basically
display advertising back
in the day before we started
doing pixel tracking.
And so I was like, this is
actually could be a different
way that we could look at
advertising attribution.
Now the challenge comes in with advertising
has always comes down to privacy,
you know, and if you're, and
then basically combing through
those log files and finding everything, it
makes it a little bit kind of old
school, but I think the concept there,
I look at it for a couple of
different ways on the image files
for chapters is that we could also utilize
that for consumption measurement.
It's, and, and, you know, I know John
Spurluck's doing a lot of fun stuff too.
And I think we all have a lot
of really good ideas out there.
It's, I'm really trying
to figure out how can
we have common language in the industry
for downloads is what we're
at right now, which is fine.
It's, it's, it, yes.
Is it the, is it ugly baby right now?
Sure.
I mean, but I think it's
the baby that we have
and I want to though figure out, okay, how
can we over the next couple of years
start going to more of a consumption?
Cause I think it's better
for the creators to
get a good understanding of like how their
content's resonating with the audience.
And then also from an
advertising standpoint,
if that is what you want
to go ahead and do.
But I think that there's, there's always
going to be the challenge of bald gardens.
And, you know, you also have other
companies like bumper who are doing,
you know, API pulls from YouTube and
Spotify based on content bite ranges,
where if there's an ad in there, you're
kind of verifying it.
So we have a lot of language going
on right now, which is fine.
I think that's great.
I just think we have to come to some sort
of consensus is a total listening hours.
That's one that we, we call
it TLH on the streaming side.
Is that something we want to
look at total listening minutes?
I feel that we need to have some sort
of common nomenclature so we can,
you know, understand
and describe our industry better to
people who are not in the industry.
So what are your favorite things besides,
so let's talk about lit
for a second, because
right now we've been pushing lit because
man, if, if, if only we could get some,
you know, everyone to kind of think about
this, it would do so much for radio.
It's like such an open door.
It baffles me that this is
not all over the place.
I would, I would totally agree.
I think that, you know, what you
guys are doing over at Godcaster,
it's when I saw your
platform was like, yeah, that's exactly,
you know, where we should be going.
I also think, I think that radio in general
is they're, they're over leveraged.
They bought a lot of sticks in the
late nineties at 13 times cashflow.
It's they're trying to figure out and now
they're having, let me translate Rocky.
What you're, the boardroom is
completely befuddled by your lingo.
When you say sticks,
you mean transmitters.
Transmitters.
They bought a lot.
Sorry.
I feel like I'm just talking, Adam knows.
Okay.
So basically they bought
a lot of transmitters.
They bought real estate at the worst mark,
at the worst time, the top of market.
And it was after
telecommunication act of 96.
And then all this crazy
stuff started happening.
It was like a land grab.
Unfortunately, what happened
is that radio became
more into real estate than
they became into content.
And you started seeing
really bad declination
of content and lack of
focus on content on there.
And so it's, it pains me because I, I
absolutely love the format of linear.
I love, I love all audio really, but
I mean, it's, it just pains me to see
like how much it's, there's certain,
there's certain sparks, you know,
you find certain stations and certain
markets that still are carrying
that great local torch for that market,
but it's, they have a challenge with it.
And then I think they're just so overwhelmed
that when you try to even bring in,
I mean, shoot, I've been,
I've been doing programmatic
and they're just finally
understanding this,
you know, probably that
past couple of years.
And I've been talking to them
for about 15 years about it.
And so I think they're slow to adopt,
but I do believe that if
they understood the concepts
of what live item tag could do for them,
especially just on an ease
of flow and work and like
workflow efficiency, I think that it
could be pretty, pretty incredible.
I think that it actually
could be something that
they could utilize that would be easier
for them to implement than probably
what they're doing right now.
So there's a lot of production.
How do we get that moving?
I mean, it just seems like what
you said, like they're, they're,
they're now real estate
guys and like, eh, whatever.
If they don't see the writing
on the wall, yeah, sure.
FM radio is still big.
AM radio to some degree, although
it's getting worse with, with EVs.
I mean, but eventually it
just makes so much sense
that the listeners want to transition.
You know, I think the in-car
experience is kind of getting there.
Um, you know, I think tune in, I don't
know how, what do you know about tune in?
How did those guys blow it so bad?
Oh man.
And it, this pains me because it's,
I look at tune in as having
like Malibu property and
having a trailer on it.
And the reason why I say that is
that they literally, I mean, they,
they did a big push like 15 years ago.
I mean, they're in the cars or
top level on, you know, Alexa.
I mean, they have like the best real
estate and like I call it, you know,
certain types of dashes, like if they're
infotainment systems, infotainment systems,
or even in the smart speaker.
And, and then they're letting
the YP, which is yellow pages.
I'm using an old nomenclature
from the shout cast days.
It's an aggregation service.
And it kills me that they're not
being better stewards of that.
And it's just because I think that would be
a huge opportunity for local podcasting.
If it was done in a way that you could
be able to, you know, like say, Hey,
listen, I'm looking for
things in Colorado.
I'm looking for whatever in
Colorado and using location tag.
And so I, I think that's another,
another one of over leverage.
It's, you know, they've been around,
I shoot, that was radio time.
I think like Bill Moore
started that back in 2003.
And so it's been around for a while.
So it does definitely have
the legacy, but it's,
it's a YP that hasn't really been taken
care of a lot lately, which
is, which is unfortunate.
I'm hoping that they're
going to turn it around
because they do have the good real estate.
They really do.
Is, so do you, you mentioned the,
y'all were talking about the Mark
Cuban broadcast.com thing earlier.
Do you think that the, it just kind of
hit me hearing you talk about this.
Do you think that the
Mark Cuban broadcast.com
type thing early on in
the digital era that
happening so early him
sort of making a billion
dollars off of everybody else's product.
Do you think that put a bad taste in
radio's mouth about digital in general?
Oh, and then put Napster on
top of that suing people.
Yeah.
I could tell you the worst years
in our industry was 2003 to 2005.
And people are like, how
do you remember that?
I'm like, because I was
basically working for
$7.45 for a startup to keep it up full.
That was spatial audio back in the day.
I mean, it, nobody wanted
to do streaming at all.
It totally killed the market.
Everybody pulled everything off.
No one even wanted to do
shoutcast streaming because
they're afraid they're going to be sued
by, you know, Fraunhofer
with the MP3 codec.
Do you remember that?
I remember those days.
Everybody went to Windows Media.
Oh, dear goodness.
WMA files.
I mean, cheer to God.
And I mean, it was really, really bad.
And, you know, when you're poor and
you don't have a job, what do you do?
You make babies.
So that's what I did.
And so it was, it was really bad.
I mean, there's only, there's, you know,
my husband's also in the
industry and I mean, we
were just trying to stay in the
industry because we saw the potential,
but Dave, you're absolutely right.
It really put a bad taste
in everyone's mouth.
And then XM came out and
then they're like, oh,
digital and satellite's going to kill.
And it's always been a
very defensive, you know,
posture that the radio industry
has had, unfortunately.
And I think they kind of looked at podcasts
like that for a while, a long time.
Oh, it's like, it's just
like everybody else is
coming after an audience instead of really
embracing it and understanding.
I will tell you that if you, to answer
your question a little bit back, Adam,
like, what would it take?
I really do believe that doing
social and chat around the, like,
that's what FM is missing right now.
That is what radio stations
are missing around.
I would say podcasts
in general is missing.
There is, we have all this great content
and all my things that I bookmark and,
you know, and I tag and I write sticky
notes of all these things that I learned.
Cause you know, according to my app,
I listened about 19 to 20
hours of podcasts per week,
which is kind of crazy.
So it's, but I get all this information,
but I have no place to have a conversation.
around it, which is a real drag.
I mean, how do you basically
connect that community so we can,
we can all collaborate
around that podcast episode.
I mean, and right now we're, we're
hacking it with like, you know,
Mastodon and all these
other little places that we're doing it.
It's very decentralized and it's, I
don't know, I don't know the solution,
but I think that is the key to unlocking.
I think that's why a lot of people go
to YouTube because it has that there.
Now, so let me ask you this too.
We have two different things.
One is we have comments, which
is the, uh, the ever existing,
never coming to fruition
cross app comments.
And then the second one is, um, gosh,
Dave, do we have a tag for chat?
Yeah.
Just chat.
And so what is kind of defaulted to is as
certainly with the boardroom and with,
uh, no agenda is this IRC
chat and we have a web IRC.
And I think, um, uh, I think
the only app that, well,
the web app that shows
it is a curio caster.
But when you say the interaction,
you're talking about chat and
not about comments, right?
Exactly.
I mean, I think, I, I, I think I
would love to see YouTube live,
the YouTube live type.
Yes.
I would think that would be great.
But I also would say that I think, I
think chat would be, cause it's more,
it's going to push
people to interact live.
That's going to be the
reason why they're going
to appointment set to go to your show.
So they can interact and that's,
I think comments are fine.
I mean, I think comments
actually benefit the, the,
the creator more than the
person who the consumer.
I think it's, I think comments
also get a little bit,
I like chat more and it's like,
I know you brought up IRC.
I was like having like, was it like
the, Oh, what was that program?
I see you, uh, that old, uh, IRC chat.
I see you and aim.
Yes.
Oh gosh.
I'm dating myself.
But I, there's also challenges
with that, of course, you know.
Well, here's the problem.
And it's, it's part, um, uh,
it's really, that's right.
I see.
There it was.
Thank you.
I see Q.
Um, part of it is, uh,
we haven't been able to move forward
because of disagreement over protocol.
Um, and of course, everybody would like
to have it decentralized and it's just,
so, you know,
you have matrix, you have, um, well, I
guess Noster, uh, is, is a version of it.
There's, uh, Dave, XMP, XMP, XMP,
XMP, and for whatever reason,
that just never happens.
And the only thing I can come up with,
because I'm seeing basically, um,
uh, although it's,
uh, void zeros, uh, system, no agenda
pays for the, no agenda stream.
Everybody's on for the, for the server.
The IRC is on the IRC for the board.
All of that is, is basically
a centralized service
that is funded by the
grace of the people who
donate to no agenda.
Wouldn't it be something
fabulous if Soundstack
just provided something
like that, that people
could just pay a few bucks for, get
it, and then it works in their app.
It's not decentralized,
but for some reason,
the decentralized part just
isn't happening with chat.
And I agree because I see it.
We had, we had over 2000 people, uh, in
our, uh, what I call the troll room, uh,
for no agenda yesterday.
I mean, it's, it's really quite amazing,
even if it's 50, it's still cool.
I mean, and it is, and I would say that's
kind of the challenge I think is that,
you know, podcasting 2.0 is really
based on decentralization, right?
I mean, I'm definitely not as smart
as you guys, but that's the idea,
but now we are going
to have centralized elements
like HLS and streaming.
It's less you want to get to peer to
peer, which it makes me a little, I mean,
I've, we've tried peering technologies
and streaming in the past.
They, they can kind of
work, but it's, it does,
it's not going to give you probably the
stability that you want.
I mean, when you press the
button and you want to stream,
you want to have consistency that
it's always going to be there.
So that's going to have
to probably come from
some form of a centralization of a server.
I mean, to be honest.
And I think so, I think some elements
as much as we want to decentralize it,
which I'm a big fan of, I think
there's gonna be some things
that we're going to have to centralize
and that's probably going to have to be
standing upstream servers and possibly,
um, you know, chatting as well.
Well, you guys basically, you
basically provide streaming servers.
That's yes.
There's a win.
Yes.
Couldn't, couldn't you just, I mean, I know
it's like, Hey, just, uh, bake that in.
It's real easy.
I'm sure it's not engineering
challenge at all.
I'm sure my product, my product
officer is going to love this.
So I, I would say that we're
always open to learning
and figuring out better
solutions for the industry.
Cause I think that let's be honest.
I mean, that would also be beneficial
to live 365, which we also do.
I mean, I totally see where
you're going on Adam on that.
And it's just, I, that would be a
whole nother area that we're not,
I would say we're pretty
good technologists.
So I would say it's something that
we could probably look at, you know,
adopting because
I think overall it just makes it more
people save with the content longer,
more people are listening.
If they are doing advertising,
that means more advertising money.
If they're doing, you know,
anything else, it's also, you know,
consumption of content,
which is also, you know, increases, you
know, everything else that we're doing.
And so I definitely see the
benefit across all sides of it.
I think it's just, you
know, our, our, is the,
is the community going
to be open to having
centralization on that?
You know, I think, yes, 100%.
It's, it's just kind of like, um,
uh, what's the term I'm looking for?
It's, uh, not, not psychological,
philosophical, maybe it is more philosophical.
It's almost philosophical.
Yeah.
I think it's a lot of that.
It's almost like religion, you know?
It is.
And I, I get it.
I definitely get it.
I mean, so I, the thing that I'm
trying to understand then is that if,
so if we are doing a
centralization on chat, then,
then all of the apps would
just be pulling from that if
the way I'm understanding it.
Right.
But it doesn't have to see that that's
air PP in the boardroom is right.
You, you can, you can have a
decentralized protocol and use it as a,
in a centralized way when necessary.
So, I mean, like that's essentially
what podcasting, I mean,
podcasting is that HTTP and RSS are
the decentralized protocols,
but you look at Buzzsprout and
RSS.com and Blueberry and, and
Transistor and all, these
are points of centralization
within a decentralized system.
There's large amounts that are pulling
from these centralized, you know,
some of these more central sources.
And that's fine, you know, because you
don't have, you don't have to do that.
You know, you can move from one
host to another if you want to,
or you can self host.
So if a podcast wanted to self, I mean,
the chat tag is there and so
it's there and it's so flexible.
You can stick any protocol
you want to in it.
So if I wanted to self host and
have my own IRC, I could do that.
Or if somebody wanted to host
on, you know, a Buzzsprout and,
or RSS.com and then, but
have their chat point to y'all to Soundstack,
you know, they could do that too.
So you don't, it's like,
I don't think it's a violation
of any sort of decentralization
points to have centralized services.
So basically then the Soundstack would
be the source of truth of sorts.
It would be basically the
repository and then it,
everything would be pulling into that.
Yeah.
I mean, especially, well,
you know, and chat is a,
chat is a sort of different animal than
comments and that kind of thing as well,
because chat is just ephemeral by nature.
I mean, you don't, you can, it doesn't
have to be, but 90% of the time it is.
People don't expect chat to
necessarily like stick around forever.
When I go back and watch a
video, a YouTube live, the,
the experience of when it was live,
that experience has already
passed and nobody's,
nobody's watching the comments or very few
people are watching the comments a
year later on an old YouTube video.
They're just watching the video.
Right.
And so, but the, the live
experience, it came and it went.
So you could like, you could
within a live experience,
have a chat where you then archive
the chat off into a time encoded
file and play it back later.
That's, that's totally, you could do that.
But most of the time people
are just wanting it for the,
for the duration of the live
event or whatever it is.
And so for that, you know,
what you're hosting, you know,
at Soundstack or wherever, what you
would be hosting is just, is just a,
a temporary room that, that spins up,
does its job and then just goes away.
Um, and so like that, that could be a
service that, you know, people pay for that.
It's like, well, I just want to, every time
I, you know, whenever I do an episode,
I want to have a chat room
that goes with it for a while.
And then it goes away sort of like, I
mean, the same with streaming, like you,
you fire up a live stream for a little
while and then it just, and then it, it,
you disconnect and you're
not live streaming anymore.
No.
And I, I, I think that's something
that we can definitely look at.
I just don't like the resources.
This is where I get over my skis as I like
to say is, and then is that, you know,
we already can spin up, you know, and
do streams that are like, like for,
like for live shows like
this, so we already kind of do that.
And it seems like it would be something
that would be within the wheelhouse.
Cause it'd be very similar to what we're
doing, which is basically, you know,
having those moments.
Cause I do think that's
really the kind of the
key to kind of unlocking a lot of this
is that is, and I know a lot of people, I
mean, I would say even like back in the,
well, SoundCloud still around,
but one of the things I did like
was their visual commenting.
I don't know if you guys remember that on
their actual linear player that they would
have, like, where are you coming
at really small, you got it,
which I thought was really
an interesting visual way of seeing, okay,
these were the hot points
of kind of like a podcast.
And then you can see commenting,
it kind of made commenting a
little bit more lasting because
it also had that visual element.
And so I think there's, there's
definitely a lot that we could be doing.
I think that, you know, by moving it
forward is, you know, how do we get,
you know, the industry
to understand, cause it
really benefits everybody.
Who does it, who, what does,
what does chatting not benefit?
It makes it more
community-based, more stick.
I would say now the people
who would not benefit would
probably be the ones who are
not obviously doing live.
And that that's where maybe commenting
becomes a little bit more important to them.
Like I would say the shows
who are not doing these
type of interview-based type of shows.
But even on your, on your, like your
player pages that you have, uh,
and the apps that
you, uh, that you bake for people, I
mean, it would be perfect there too.
Yeah.
It seems like something
that would be good for any
type of live stream
environment, regardless
of whether it's in a podcast app or not.
I would agree.
I mean, I would say like, what do
you guys think the challenges like,
like for instance,
like trying to promote
podcasting 2.0 more?
I mean, how do we kind of get the
larger PIC to understand the,
the value of what, what's
going on within, you know, podcasting
2.0 and the podcast standards project?
Is it having more panels at, you know,
podcast movement or I'm trying
to figure out the angle
here to kind of help bring together
the industry a little bit better.
Well, my opinion is you just published,
the more people are publishing
with these new tags,
the more, uh, people in development
rooms look at it and go, huh,
what could I do with this?
It's it doing it from the top
down is very, very difficult.
Yeah.
I mean, I don't know,
Dave, your, your thoughts.
Yeah.
No, I, I agree.
And this, this is one of the reasons why,
why podcasting the 2.0
project has been, has
had success over the last
five years is because
the hosting companies
jumped in and were early
adopters when there was very few
apps that supported these features.
They jumped in and said, okay,
we're going to do, uh, you know,
we're going to put this,
this, and this tag into our feeds.
We're going to declare
the namespace and then
we're going to put in
chapters, transcripts
and soundbites and, you
know, maybe a couple more.
And there's some, there's some company, I
mean, like blueberry, they dove in with,
I mean,
they went all the way, the head hair wet
all the way under, you know, I mean,
they went in with the, the full
rundown of every single tag and they,
they bet sort of bet the farm
of development time on that content.
And then now you have this
wealth of content and
when you have a humongous
wealth of content,
it's just like, um, it's like
corn in a field for developers.
They can't resist, you know,
they just, they have to go,
they see all this content and they
think, oh man, I could
do such cool things with
chapter tags or this and
this and this and this.
So they, I think it's like
bait, you know, you're, you're,
you're baiting developers
to come do cool stuff.
And so like thinking about, yeah, just
thinking about Soundstack, you know,
I mean, y'all's wheelhouse
is obviously live streaming.
I mean, you do a bunch of stuff,
but the ability, you know,
the ability to spin up a live stream,
do it, throw the live, you
know, item tag into a feed.
And then that kind of stuff that one,
it's like when you start
doing it from the content
side, apps, just like,
it's like they salivate.
They, the developers want to do, want
to do cool stuff with that thing.
And so I think that's the only
way we have been successful.
All the attempts at marketing, man,
they've, they've always been a mixed bag.
Like, I mean, like, you know, we've all,
a lot of people have
tried to market and, and
the podcast centers project has
done, you know, they've done, uh,
the work they've done really
is just pulling themselves together.
Um, they, yes, they have done
marketing, but like the,
the reason that things get adopted
is not because somebody tells you to, it's
because developers begin to do things.
And then one person sees another person do
it when, you know, the biggest inflection
points has been when, uh,
Apple adopted transcripts,
when Pocket Cast started
adopting open source
tags, uh, I mean, uh, podcasting 2.0
tags, uh, these have been like when one,
so then, you
know, and then like, uh, Transistor
adopted, uh, the social interact tag,
Buzzsprout adopted pod,
uh, adopted pod role.
And then podcast, Pocket Cast picked
it up the, you know, fountain, um,
RSS.com and a couple
of others put in the value tag.
And then, uh, you know, fountain
started ingesting that there's,
there's like somebody will do
something and then somebody else sees
it and picks it up and runs with it.
And so, you know, I'm not saying that
marketing is useless in this regard,
but it's like, what really happens
is, is people in the industry seeing
other people in the industry do things
and because it is, you know, there's a,
there's a little bit of
competition factor where, you
know, they have this feature
and we need to have it too.
There's a little bit of
that, but I think it's,
I think it's less of that and more of,
especially now that the
podcast standards project has,
has sort of really united a lot of, a
lot of the feelings around
moving the industry forward.
I think, I think there
really is a sort of like
shared ideal between the podcast standards
project participants where they really do
all want to move the industry forward.
And, and that means that
they're sort of marketing
to apps now saying here
we're now, so, you know,
we're supporting this tag
and this tag and this tag,
please come do something with it now.
So I think that's where the voice, maybe,
maybe that's where the voices
become important because
you, you can say, you know, we're,
Hey, you know, Hey developers,
we're giving you cool stuff.
Let's see what you can do with it.
And then I would say
it's the app's job then
to translate that to the listener value.
Yes.
Yeah.
But, but without the publishing
part, it never happens.
Agreed.
This, you have to be pushing it.
You have to be publishing.
That's why transcripts went through
because everybody jumped on transcripts.
Um, I think there's a reasonable
selection that does, um, the, uh,
cloud-based chapters,
but I think really, uh,
the ones that we've,
that we've been pushing
is the funding tag right
now because there's been such a
phenomenal change in the app stores, uh,
which is a big, big deal and, uh, you
know, but I don't know, Dave, how many,
how many companies push the funding tag?
Do you, I guess we could look.
Oh, it's quite a, it's quite a few.
I mean, it's one of the more adopted tags.
Take a look.
Then take a look as well.
Um, cause we have stats for this Rocky.
No, we have, uh, podcastindex.org.
Uh, let me see.
Okay.
Where's the funding?
Funding.
Let's see.
What are we doing?
Hosting or apps?
Uh, but well, hosting, hosting, hosting.
Hosting.
Okay.
Let's see.
Castgarden, Blueberry, PowerPress,
Sovereign Feet, Podhome, RSSBlue,
RSS.com, Castapod, Captivate.
Quite a few actually.
Yeah, Transistor, Buzzsprout,
Dystopia, Fireside, Red Circle.
I mean, it's like tons.
Yeah, tons.
So that, that will
eventually start surfacing.
I'm pretty sure, at least
I hope some of the 2.0
apps are going to do a better job of it.
A lot of them already
show it in a good place.
Um, and the tag also allows
you to, uh, determine text.
So you can say, instead of just being
a generic button, it can be, you know,
it can be some text in there, like give
to our show or donate or buy me lunch,
whatever you want to put in there.
Um, so that's one.
And then I think, I think at this
point we should, at least I'll just,
whenever I mentioned
the lit tag for live, I think along with
that has to come, um, chat somehow,
some form of
chat just, and I think, don't I, do I put
something in our chat tag for this show?
Let me see.
I keep scrolling up and down the
podcasting, the podcast apps.com list.
I'm just not seeing Soundstack on here.
Yeah.
What's wrong with those people?
I know you declare the
feed and you use tags.
What?
Somebody, somebody's got to
give us a pull, pull request.
Yeah, I think so.
Yeah.
You got to put yourself on the side.
So wait, so I, I'm looking
at, um, sovereign feeds.
I don't think there's a, I thought
there was a chat thing in there.
Uh, he was, he used to be
using the chat attribute,
but I think he switched to use the
chat, uh, I thought he did.
I don't see it.
Um, let me see, find, let's see chat.
Nope.
It's not in there anymore.
Hmm.
Oh wait, there it is.
Now there it is.
Uh, yeah, under, yeah, exactly.
Under live item status equals live.
There you go.
Chat equals IRC zero node.net.
So we're publishing it.
Uh, but of course, you
know, in that case, uh,
the app would have to understand IRC would
have to become an IRC
client and IRC is anything
but friendly when it comes to newbies.
Yeah, I would.
And then I would say that if
I'm remembering on the IRC,
why it kind of went out of favor
was more of like exploitation.
If I'm remembering correctly,
I mean, I'm going back.
It wasn't enough porn.
That was the problem.
I wasn't going to say that,
but that's a good way.
Welcome to the boys club.
Yeah.
Well, that's okay.
It's like, there's never a room,
you know, line of the bathroom.
So I'm used to it.
So it's like, uh, it's like, I'm always
like have it to myself, but it's,
I think as IRC, you're right.
It's not the most user-friendly, but I
would say it's not the hardest either.
I mean, I've seen worse.
Well, the registration part is
where it becomes difficult.
And I mean, running an IRC server,
that's the problem because
you think it's like, oh,
I'm just running an IRC server.
Then you get net splits and
people hijacking your channel.
If you don't register it and all the
commands are command line, like, you know,
it's like,
well, I would say the first person,
the first, the first group to do this,
like, would you
said, centralize this in a way that
makes it easy for people to do it?
That pro the product, whatever
protocol that, that, that,
that gets picked for that, that
just becomes becomes the default.
Yeah.
I mean, maybe it's XMPP, you know,
who knows, because that's, I mean,
that's old, you know,
that's the old jabber protocol.
Uh, it's very, you know,
it's a very simple protocol.
It's not complicated, but there
could be a, there's a ton.
But you still, you still need an, you
still need an XRPP server somewhere.
Yeah.
But you can spend one of those up.
That's, that's not the end
of the world, you know?
Right.
Well, it's the first person that does it.
It just becomes, it just
becomes the de facto.
Well, but that's not true
because we've been publishing
the IRC in our chat and
it has become nothing.
Well, but we, you know, we don't, but
it, but it works for our show, but no,
no one's logging in through
any podcast app and using it.
Well, probably because the podcast apps,
what they're doing is
just ignoring clicking.
No, no.
Well, well, some of them are,
but like what, like think,
I think what Podverse does is
just opens up a web view.
Yes.
Yeah.
With book.
So, but if it's done right with
the chat tag, then, then you're,
you're integrating at
a protocol level, you know, so, and, and
at that point you, you can actually,
it's like,
if you look at, if you look at the podcast
index side, you know, if you go to,
I think it's this show, um,
let's see, podcast 2.0.
Yeah.
If you go to our show, you
know, there's the, um,
the comments are posted at
the bottom of each episode.
That's the social interact tag.
Right.
And it's a threaded, it's threaded comments
that are attached to each episode.
If you hit show comments
and that's pulling off.
A decentralized, uh, activity pub.
Yeah.
And then that, the same thing can happen.
That's a, that's an integration.
Whereas, whereas what's
happening with the chat
in apps is mostly just sort of like open
a webpage with an R with IRC on it.
But if it was more like this, if
it was more like a, you know,
a true integration, then that
becomes, that would just
become the de facto standard.
I think, but also because
you, a lot of, you know,
a lot of the early adopter apps are
going to be, you know,
are open source as well.
And not all of them, but a lot
of them are, uh, you know,
and pod verse antenna pod, you
know, then, and so you, you would
also maybe get libraries out of that.
And we, you know, we
could do that as soon.
We could integrate it directly
into, into the website.
Yeah.
I just think there'd be a lot, you
know, there's a, there's a lot there.
There is a lot there.
And I mean, I'm even thinking in the back
of my head is like the gamification,
um, of your highest donators and you know,
how you could utilize that even within,
like within the chat as well.
I mean, there's, you're absolutely right.
There's so many ways that
you could, you know,
if they're like similar to like how you do
Adam on no agenda where you, you know,
you have your different, you know,
levels of, of,
of, of supporters and, and it's amazing
what a little icon next to your name does.
Oh yeah.
Okay.
So true fans, true fans, uh, and look
at true fans and look at fountain.
Yeah.
Both, both of them are
integrating, commenting.
They do.
Yeah, they're, they're integrating
live chat and commenting heavily.
Fountain's doing it with
Noster true fans is
doing it internally and then publishing it
out with activity pub.
So other, you know, they're not, well,
fountain is, I was about to say,
they're not doing hosting
fountain is doing hosting now that they've
done the integration with RSS blue.
But, um, I think, you know,
those are examples of true integration
that has happened at the app level.
And so if we can just sort of like decent,
you're like, or not decentralized,
but sort of like pull back from that
and give them the thing they need,
then they can show it in app without
even having to do anything.
Well, so it'll take the PSP group to
start publishing those tags because that,
you know,
that's the problem right there is it
has to come from the hosting companies.
Hosting companies have to
make it, uh, you know,
have to make this field available and
give the people some options to use.
And then the, the apps will that,
it just always happens that way.
Once you start publishing, then
the apps will follow that.
That just seems to always be the way.
When you, when you back.
So like, and, and for the hosting
side, it doesn't really matter.
And I've said this, I feel like
I've said this a hundred times.
It doesn't really matter
what you do internally,
because you can have your
own system internally,
as long as you publish in
an open standards way.
Like, so you could have your own
internal system for chat and that,
that is whatever you want it to be.
But as long as you, as
long as you put it in the
feed as a chat tag and
then make it accessible
through a protocol that other people
understand, an open standards protocol,
that's all, that's all it takes.
It's like, you can really just slice
and dice this thing however you want.
Well, you know, I tried to do,
I did this with the MKUltra thing
was the year and a half ago.
Right.
Which was basically a, you know, a
hacked up version of, of Helipad to,
to be a con, an ephemeral chat server.
And that, that code still exists.
You know, you can use that.
It wasn't, it was Nostra based, but
it still exists and it'll, you know,
it can give you a temporary chat
room and then it just goes away.
So that's before we, that was
even before we had the chat tag.
So it would actually make even
more sense now, but you know,
that could have gone out, even
though it was, it was Nostra internally,
it can go out as activity pub or anything.
Yeah.
I just, I think, I just think
there's so many ways to do this.
Well, I think it's a good thing
to focus on because, you know,
if we got funding, which
already is, has a lot of
adoption, that's good.
And the apps can follow suit and
particularly for value for value.
And I just, it seems
like a no brainer to me.
And I think, um, true
fans really has that one
figured out and fountain is
doing a version of that.
Um, then if you have the lit tag
combined with chat and pod ping,
that's another, another important one.
Um, you know, Rocky, to answer
your question more directly, if,
if you set it up so that
there is a session or something
that is, cause Dave and Adam,
we're very unorganized.
This is, this is our, this is our brand.
Okay.
This is our brand.
We are anything but organized.
And, uh, and so in fact, we
have a, you know, Godcaster,
we have Gordon and he's organized
and, you know, and he organizes
us and it's fantastic.
So if, if at any point you
think there's a conference
where we can have an organized discussion,
I'd love to do it with you,
um, I would come out for that.
I mean, the thing.
Well, I'm glad that you
brought that up, Adam.
Actually, I do have.
Oh, no.
Did I just walk right into it?
Oh, goodness.
You totally walked into it.
So, Hey, you put me on the hot sale,
I'll put you on your, so we do have,
uh, Soundstack, we, we
have sponsored a stage.
And with that, we do
get, I call it airtime.
We get a panel and we are willing
to give that to podcasting 2.0.
And Adam, you know where it's at.
Cause you were just there for NRB.
Oh, is it Nashville?
Yeah.
No, it's at the Gaylord
and the Texan Gaylord.
Oh, yeah.
Oh, and when is this?
This is what, what, what conference?
It's the podcast movement.
Well, would you do it with me?
And then, and I would do it with you.
If anybody else, I mean, whoever
else we think would be, you know,
additive to that conversation
would absolutely love to have it.
And I think it would.
Screw that.
Just you and me, baby.
We don't need anybody else.
Don't convolute it.
No, no.
Hey, you got the top
dog, top billing here.
We're not going to water
it down with anybody else.
I would love it.
Cause I think that it's, it's really good.
I know that's more of the PIC.
It's becoming more of that side of it.
But I also think that a lot
of folks don't understand
the power of what they're missing.
And it's, I've been trying to explain
it and, and I am not as geeky.
I'm geeky to a point, but I
am not as geeky as you guys.
And I just want to help
build this industry and
get all the great content out there and
make, it's really about the listeners.
I mean, at the end of the day, it's that
community around the listeners and I,
gosh, we're doing
so many cool things and we're not
giving them any place to give us,
give us feedback and talk to them.
It's like, we're very much broadcast
right now where it's a, you know,
we are going, we're telling them,
but we're not getting it back.
And I think the, the, the platforms,
social and everything else, it's that too,
even if we make chat into comments, I mean,
cause you have to understand it's not,
chat's not going to be great
for every single podcast.
And I'm not saying we have
to be over inclusive and
making of a solution that
works with everybody
because that's, that's ridiculous.
It's never going to work.
But I do think that even, you know,
like chat that goes to comments
where people can go ahead
and even have, I remember when I had an
internet radio station, we used to run BBSs.
I'm totally dating myself.
I mean, yeah, like virtual
BBS and all this other ones.
And yes, they would totally get hacked
all the time, but it's like, so that's,
I mean, that's the hard thing
is the moderation of it.
But even in a linear station
where it was a metal
station and people are just like, I want
to talk about dream theater, you
know, some, you know, like, you know,
eight minute songs, you know,
dear God goes on forever.
That's a lot of time to chat, but
it's crazy because I look at Reddit,
Reddit basically is nothing but a
commenting, you know, bulletin board system.
And, and so I think that if there's
a way that we can make a commenting,
a chat to comment,
or even just comments on podcasts that
really don't have that live element,
but are still
quite good in what they're doing and
the storytelling and everything else,
I think it could be, I think
of all the economic podcasts.
And if I had the opportunity to,
to kind of like suss out some
things that I'm thinking,
I think it'd be really cool,
even if it's not in life.
Here's what I'd say.
So just remembering back five
years now, I think Dave,
going back to the early days when
we were just starting up
with the podcast index and
there was excitement
and people are talking
about tags and the big problem
for app developers in general,
and even with the, with the social
interact tag is moderation.
And so we, what we can't have
is we can't have moderators.
No one can afford it.
There's weight.
There's a huge pain in the butt.
What I love about IRC is
the ephemeral nature of it.
You can say the most horrible
things and it's gone.
You know, it just, it just goes away.
And I think that's perfect for
podcasting even beyond YouTube, because,
you know, then
you get, I think this is what, what's
holding app developers back is, well,
then, you know,
someone wants to have the comments
turned off and where does that happen?
And, you know, someone says something
slanderous and it's in my system.
I mean, these are all the problems of,
uh, that come with decentralization.
And so I'm kind of thinking like,
wow, you know, and by the way,
the fountain guys don't care.
They're fine.
They, they use Nostar and Nostar
is, you know, you, it's out there.
You, there's no takesies backsies.
It's done.
You can't, you can't delete it.
It's permanent, which
is, which is also okay.
But I really love the idea of
something that just goes away.
So you're interacting with
people, you're shouting.
Cause that's what it is.
It's, I always say, you know, no agenda
and the same with the boardroom.
It's a live studio audience and, um, I've
developed a, um, uh, my peripheral vision.
I take in what's going on
in the chat room and it's,
and sometimes it's hurtful, irksome,
you know, infuriating.
Um, but I know it's gone.
It's like in 20 more lines,
it's going to be gone.
It'll be out of view.
And I think if we can just get
something like that started, man,
that would be so dynamic.
I would say get that started.
And then I would say on
the commenting side,
moderation is actually
quite cheap with AI now.
I just say, I know I threw it out there.
I know you're throwing Molotov
cocktails in the boardroom.
I mean, on the way out
podcast movement appearances.
I'm not going to do that.
Hey, I'm just through,
I'm not that I agree.
I'm just saying there's,
there's ways they can do it.
Cause I do remember even when I used
to run the internet radio stations,
run metal stations and
I would agree with you.
It was a lot of moderation in the BBSs
where I was just, it took a lot of time,
but it's oh my gosh, a lot.
And I, and I think, but
I do agree with you.
I mean, let's, cause I think chat is going
to basically help drive live item tags.
That's going to help drive streaming.
Um, not that I, I want to kill the download
by any means, but I just think it's,
I think it's going to start
going away much like,
I think we're going to
become more like, you
know, video where if I'm going to be
hopping on a plane and I want to,
I'll download it cause I'm going to
be offline, so to speak, you know,
even that's kind of going
away at this point.
Cause I mean, I was noticing
that on my long haul
flight coming back from
Europe that actually
United was allowing me
to download podcasts,
which I thought was kind of interesting.
Yeah.
So they're opening it up.
I don't think I could do full blown,
you know, like high definition video,
but I think it's such a, it's a small,
such a like light type of agent.
It's not really that big of a deal.
So I do see that, you know, we're our, we
still have, we have progressive downloads.
I mean, I think the next iteration is
going to be some form of streaming.
I don't think it's going to be all of it,
but I definitely think
it's going to move towards
that as we kind of get that.
And I'm not saying that downloads
are going away cause I got, I have,
I'm putting salve
on my back from like talking about it
at the IEV cause everybody's like,
yo, the download.
I'm like, ah, guys, I know I'm
just saying in the future, future,
we got to think about the future.
So when is a podcast movement in Dallas?
I knew you're going to ask me this.
Okay.
Well, how unprepared are you?
I mean, come on, you've
got me on the hook now.
I do have you on the hook.
It's August.
Let's see.
I think it's August 18th.
Yeah.
The week of August 18th through.
That's a good, that's a good one for me.
Most of the stuff works.
I would say most of the
panels are on the 19th
and 20th would be pretty
much the core of it.
So 20th, 20th.
Yes.
19th and 20th possible, 21 not possible.
Okay.
Then we'll just make sure
it's on the 19th or 20th.
I got the pull.
I'll make it happen.
I know you do.
Dallas, Dallas is so close.
You can ride up, ride up
there on your e-bike.
Dude, I'm going to fly in.
I'm going to be cool.
I'm going to fly myself in.
Oh, you're for the Cessna?
Yeah.
The Cessna.
Excuse me.
The G2.
I'm sorry.
The G4.
G4.
Okay.
G4 SR22 G4 Turbo, baby.
Yeah.
I mean, it's a rental, but still.
It's a rental.
Yeah, but we're, I mean,
we're definitely willing to do that
because I think it's, it's just,
and plus, I mean, you don't come out that
often, Adam, I'll be honest with you.
No, I don't because the last
time we did podcast movement,
they shoved us in the back room during
lunch and like, congratulations,
no marketing, no nothing.
Just, you know why?
Because we weren't paying for it.
Well, sometimes I, I, I, I have spoken
at every single podcast movement.
I don't know if I want to like,
and I think it's because I just have
really like geeky conversations.
And so I, I know you're, like,
I was trying to do ad insertion
back in like, I don't know, 2016.
And, you know, I think it was me and Rob
Greeley and like five people in the,
in like a, like a broom closet.
So I definitely understand
how that kind of goes.
So, but I think it's, I think it's,
it's ready for it's, you know, it's,
it's like, you know,
debutante ball, so to speak.
I think it's ready.
I think it's, it's, it's, it's now
gotten to the point, not that we,
what we have been doing for, you know,
four to five years is, is that loss.
I think now is the time that we're
going to start seeing that people,
it's going to start clicking for people.
I mean, it's clicking.
You just need a click baity title.
The title of the session is why,
why the download is dead or something
just going to piss everybody off.
Yeah.
It's the PIC.
You have to throw a bomb
to get attention in there.
That's true.
Hey, not, not that there's anything else.
Some of my best friends are PIC.
It's something like, it's,
it's got to be something more
like why you're not making the
most money possible from your podcast.
Yeah.
20, 20 tips to hack your
podcast monetization.
Yeah.
Something like that.
That's why I'm very glad
that you agreed to that.
Cause what we wanted to do was
something that was different.
And cause I think everybody's over, if I
hear one more, you know, panel or any,
or discussion about video,
I might shoot my wrist.
Um, you know, there's a
programmatic as much as I love it.
And I've been doing it for a while.
I just feel that it's, it's still there.
It's just the train is kind of road.
I think it's ready to have
some more invigoration
on something that's
around content and really
driving the industry
together with everything.
So I'm very excited.
Rocky, you and me, how tall are you?
If you don't mind me asking.
Oh, I am five, four.
I am not a big woman.
Okay.
We're going to be sitting down.
We'll be sitting down.
Cause otherwise we're the odd couple.
We'll, we'll be sitting
down, but we'll do demos.
We'll talk.
We'll, we'll, we'll, I mean,
you're super exciting.
We'll stream it live.
We'll do it lit.
We'll have, we'll have a, we'll
specifically invite a C Brooklyn one, one,
two to talk horrible
things in the chat room.
And cotton gin and all these guys
to say horrible, horrible things.
Uh, I'll bring along
the boost to gram sign,
the boobery made so
people can make it light
up different with their different boosts.
We'll make it awesome.
Oh, I I'm excited.
I, I, that's exactly what I want to do.
And I think that this is,
this is perfect timing.
I really do.
I think it's good timing
in the industry right now.
And I think it's, it's time to kind
of like, uh, to really push this.
I think the best part of this is that
you have to do it and I don't have to,
that's the best part of this.
Well, there you go.
Um, but I really appreciate the invitation,
although I kind of invited myself.
I know I was, I was hoping
you were going to ask,
or I was going to put you on the spot.
So you kind of made the
opening really easy for me.
So that's, that's good.
No, it's, it's perfect
because you know, it's paid.
So we know that we'll get promotion.
That's the, that's the,
that's a great part.
Um, and you know, when we'll,
we'll come up with a funny time.
You're, you're a dynamic
speaker, so it'll, it'll be fun.
We'll, we'll have some, it'll be
the one where people go, Oh man,
were you at that session
with Curry and Thomas really?
I'm sorry.
Yes.
Rocky and Adam.
Yeah.
There you go.
And I'm going to start it off.
It's like, that's like a morning show.
Curry.
Yeah.
I'll be your sidekick.
It's perfect.
It's the morning show.
It will, it will be, it'll be really good.
And I think it's a, I think this
is what we need to be doing.
So more of this type of stuff.
I know you don't come out that night and
Dave, I don't know if you ever leave.
I don't think you ever leave Alabama,
but I've never left this house.
That's okay.
I'm fine being, you know, like
being the facing person of this.
And I think the goal is really to
translate a lot of what we're doing.
And I think what you
probably did at the NRB
with Godcaster was probably a lot of it.
It's just really like seeing
the application of it.
Cause I think a lot of
people just think it's the
geek people in this tech
bubble and we don't
understand it and I just really, I
want to show the possible, you know,
it really comes
down to increased consumption community,
uh, like I take an old term stickiness,
um, making sure that people are
really staying with your content
and then whatever you want to do, value
for value advertising, it all
benefits at the end of the day.
And that's the goal of
it is to constantly make
sure this industry is here in five years.
Just don't do it all.
That's the mistake I made.
That is a hard thing.
Cause there's so many
things to talk about.
My, my session, the, the session
that me and Adam did in, uh,
that we got stuck back in
the back room after lunch was,
you know, Adam, Adam did like,
you know, a 10 minute intro.
And then I did the whole
rest of the session trying
to go through like 20 tags in 30 minutes.
And it was, it was horrible.
It was like a head snapper, you know,
that, that was, that was a bad decision.
Um, Rocky, uh, I'll tell you,
but if you don't mind just
hanging on for a little bit,
we're going to thank some
people and I want you
to go look at your fountain app and tell
me that I have been
looking in the background.
It's been quite exciting.
I'm getting, I'm getting stuff, getting
stuff, you're getting stuff, money, baby.
That's money.
That's money in the pocket.
Isn't that cool though?
How it just comes in.
Click, click, click, click, click.
It is very cool.
And I have to say thank you to
everybody who, who has given me stats.
I, I'm very, uh, very, it's very
kind and I'm very grateful.
So very cool.
So, uh, which I will give, which
I will give to everybody else.
And I have stats in there.
I'm very excited.
I'm glad you did this because I, that, and
you'll see it because it only become more
when, when we publish the show, you
know, this is the live, the, the,
the live sats, but when people start
listening, you'll just see it.
You'd be like, wow, where'd I get
this $100 from all of a sudden?
Which, which is great.
I'll just recirculate it back into
the industry, which is great.
That's fun stuff.
So, uh, boost that came in live
during the show, Lyceum 100 sats.
Great to hear.
Well, great to hear.
Uh, oh wait, 1776, a freedom
boost from Lyceum as well.
Rocky is rocking the show.
Go podcasting.
Liberty and freedom of expression.
Best premises.
That's Martin Lindeskog,
uh, by the way, Lyceum.
Uh, Mike Dell, uh, comes
in from Castamatic,
which now does the live and
lit, uh, which we love.
And he says, hi Rocky, uh, one,
two, three, four, Satoshi,
Sam from true fans coming in
from true fans, uh, triple seven.
We can't wait for the PSP
or existing hosts like
fountain will be a host
and app and implement
live chat and video by HLS.
Uh, Sam's going to do all Sam
and the, ladies and gentlemen,
Sam Sethi and the kitchen sink.
Yes.
It's the band you always wanted to see.
Uh, Bob Rathmel.
That sounds like a new person to me.
Bob Rathmel.
Have you heard Bob Rathmel before today?
Oh, defrag him.
I'm defrag him.
And he's coming in from Podverse and
he says, interesting discussion.
All right.
Great.
Is that like saying I have
a good personality or?
Yeah, exactly.
She's got a great personality.
Uh, thousand stats from Cole McCormick.
He says, this is a bit off topic,
but I want the boardroom
to know one of the largest
YouTubers, YouTubers ever
PewDiePie put out a video
this week about how much he hates Google
and has been self-hosting
his passwords using
Linux and transitioning to
Graphene OS for his phone.
The conversation of openness and
decentralization is growing rapidly.
If PewDiePie is on it.
Yeah, definitely.
Although I just, I just
saw the Graphene OS guys
flipping out the other day
because, uh, ASOP, that's the.
Yeah.
The non Google.
The, so they're removing
support for, uh, pixel devices.
Oh, really?
Which is pretty much the only thing
that Graphene really runs well on.
That sucks.
Yeah.
Goodbye, Graphene.
You know what that, that's a move, man.
That's a move.
That's, that's what they do over there.
Harvhat, triple seven, just the boost.
He says, thank you very much.
And a seven, seven, seven, seven,
seven from, uh, from Harvhat.
And he says, just like magic.
And he's coming in from the boost CLI.
And that's that, uh, that heavenly
sound you heard earlier, Rocky.
That's when someone sends in a 77, 77.
You can, we've, we've
rigged all this stuff.
I mean, it's like.
It got triggers.
Yeah, exactly.
So when, when someone sends a
boost, it, uh, not always some,
the boost bot may be broken,
but it'll show up in the
chat and there's all
kinds of cool stuff we developed that just
needs to be, um, implemented by, uh,
live three 65, uh, 1821 from Pfeiffer.
He says, cue eye of the
tiger, Rocky boost.
There you go.
Never heard that one before.
Uh, bitpunk.fm 424 boosting the log man.
Yeah, there we go.
And a confirmation from salty crayon.
He got the bat signal.
And I have one more here.
22, 22 from the ugly
ducking, ugly quacking duck.
It's Bruce.
I have a car, Carhartt wallet.
Does that count?
It seems to have trouble hanging
on to any fiat currency.
I put in it using the Albie hub started
with Albie Walt in the beginning.
Enjoyed your, oh, this is from last week.
Franco go podcasting.
Thanks again.
Oh yeah.
I'm using chapters two, LOL 73, 73s.
And with that, I believe
I have hit the delimiter.
So you're up my friend.
We had such a good show last week
with Franco that we got no PayPal.
Zero.
Way to go.
Franco.
Can't wait to have you on again.
Yeah.
Look for the call.
Boost.
See, but we did get some boost.
See loss on Linux.
One, two, three, four through fountain.
He says, Franco was a good guest.
Thank you.
See loss.
Appreciate it.
I agree.
Concur.
Except for, except for the donations.
See loss on Linux again.
One, two, three, four through fountain.
He says, can we just
accept that key send is
over and concentrate on getting
everything set up again?
It was one step wrong while
running with scissors.
Feels like we need to recover quickly.
I think it's happening.
I think, uh, I think things are happening.
At least it's gonna, I don't think
it can be a, I don't think you,
you burn it and start over.
I think it's a transition to it.
Yeah.
It's a transition.
Well, you know, 90, 90%
of the sets come from,
come from fountain and
they've transitioned.
They are, they are a trans app.
In fact, they're a trans app.
Yes.
And the fountain from now on to be
known as they, them, uh, Chris Lass.
Yeah.
From Jupiter Broadcasting.
Jupiter Broadcasting.
20,000 sets.
Very nice.
Thank you so much, Chris.
Through fountain.
Okay.
So make Chris.
Let me make sense out of this one.
Chris Lass.
20,000 sets.
Through fountain.
He says, so excited about
lit supporting Castamatic.
Great work.
He sent it through fountain.
Well, there you go.
Chris.
He's just a cheerleader.
He's just, he's just excited.
That's good.
This week in Bitcoin is
my always go to podcast.
I love that podcast.
And the delimiter, comic strip blogger,
CSB, 14,010 sets through fountain.
He says, howdy, Dave and Adam.
Fetty verse is full of
skeptics to put it mildly.
And I'm being asked there, quote,
which is worser, Keeper Show or MoFax?
Unquote.
And I say it's unfair because
the MoFax podcast is no mo.
So I again recommend a podcast
from www.curryandthekeeper.com.
Oy, Bitcoin bros from
Podcasting 2.0 community.
Please send Bitcoin grams to
Curry and the Keeper podcast.
Evangelical pastors and I, a dumb Polak,
cannot bear the burden of
donating Bitcoin there forever.
Yo, CSB.
Thank you, CSB.
I love that he just promotes
other podcasts all the time.
That is, he is, he's a special
place for him in heaven.
Very special place.
We got some monthlies.
Michael Goggin, $5.
Jorge Hernandez, $5.
Cohen Glotzbach, $5.
Christopher Reamer, $10.
James Sullivan, $10.
Jordan Dunville, $10.
Michael Kimmerer, $5.33.
Chris Bernardik, $5.
And Dreb Scott, $15.
Thank you all very much.
If you want to support the
podcastindex.org project,
which is where all of these funds go to,
go to podcastindex.org at the bottom.
There's a big red donate button.
You can send us your fiat
fund coupons that way.
But of course, we love the boosts,
which also go directly into
the podcast index node.
And Daniel J, Daniel J,
I need to have your full node to be
able to open up liquidity to you.
I posted it on the Mastodon,
but I guess I didn't see it.
Because we're happy to give you liquidity.
We're happy to open up a channel to you.
And thank you again for
supporting Podcasting 2.0.
And Rocky, thank you so much for
taking the time to be with us today.
Long overdue.
Oh, this is too much fun.
I mean, I might have to make
this like a gig, you know.
Come on.
It's like it's fun.
Well, yeah, you'll have
to come back so we can
promote our appearance
at Podcast Movement.
That's right.
Yes.
Now, where do I get my glossies?
Do I send those to you and
my bio and all that stuff?
Yeah, I'll have my people
talk to your people, yes.
Okay.
Well, I know you have people.
That's the best part, Rocky.
Yes.
No, you do most of your stuff yourself.
I've seen you.
Yeah, I do.
Because it's full, it's
riddled full of errors.
So you can definitely
tell AI is not doing it.
All right.
So what are you doing this weekend, Rocky?
This weekend, I'm probably working wood.
Okay.
She's working wood.
From log man to woodworker.
Working wood with log man.
There we go.
We burn 10 quarts of wood a year.
So we drop trees and I'm splitting
wood and stacking it most likely.
Oh man, you're like trad wife almost.
I'm going to work and burn some wood.
We like to call ourselves technecks.
Yeah, technology rednecks.
Technecks.
Oh, another show title.
Oh my God.
This is out of control.
Out of control.
Brother Dave, have
yourself a great weekend.
You too, bro.
And thank you very much, board meeting.
Rocky, thanks again.
We really appreciate you.
My pleasure.
I look forward to podcast
movement in Dallas in August.
And we'll be back next week right here.
Podcasting 2.0.
See you then, everybody.
Bye-bye.
You have been listening to Podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcastindex.org
for more information.
Go podcasting!
This doesn't make sense.
I'm freaking out inside.